<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MVBC</title>
    <description>Montana Vikings Basketball Club</description>
    <link>http://mvbc.co.za/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mvbc.co.za/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 11:17:10 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 11:17:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>MVBC 24 Hour Basketball Marathon 2016!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;24 Hour Basketball Marathon 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Montana Vikings Basketball Club (MVBC) 24 Hour Basketball Marathon is an event where all members of the club get together to participate in basketball themed activities continuously for 24 hours. The idea behind the event was to create an environment where the entire club could get together and do the thing we love most – play basketball. Throughout the course of the event members from across all age groups team up to compete for 20 minute periods, resulting in scenarios where under 12 girls end up sharing the court with players from our senior men’s teams. Due to the fact that this event focuses more on the fun aspect than the winning, these moments become quite special for our juniors who aspire to become great basketball players one day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At MVBC, we use every club event to deliver a positive message, and impart valuable life skills to our juniors. These are in the form of social awareness sessions, talks from our seniors about their life experiences, and sessions from external community organisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event has grown tremendously since its inception in 2000, and with a club membership of 120 active players, along with parents, friends and non-playing members, we have been able to generate hype around the event. In 2012 and 2013 &amp;amp; 2016 KFM covered the event, and in the past we’ve had Hectic99 presenters covering it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/event/2016/04/22/24hour-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/event/2016/04/22/24hour-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>24 Hour 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;24 Hour Basketball Marathon 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/kfm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;KFM Team&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVBC on the Ryan O&#39;Connor Show - KFM 21 April 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Montana Vikings Basketball Club (MVBC) 24 Hour Basketball Marathon is an event where all members of the club get together to participate in basketball themed activities continuously for 24 hours. The idea behind the event was to create an environment where the entire club could get together and do the thing we love most – play basketball. Throughout the course of the event members from across all age groups team up to compete for 20 minute periods, resulting in scenarios where under 12 girls end up sharing the court with players from our senior men’s teams. Due to the fact that this event focuses more on the fun aspect than the winning, these moments become quite special for our juniors who aspire to become great basketball players one day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At MVBC, we use every club event to deliver a positive message, and impart valuable life skills to our juniors. These are in the form of social awareness sessions, talks from our seniors about their life experiences, and sessions from external community organisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event has grown tremendously since its inception in 2000, and with a club membership of 120 active players, along with parents, friends and non-playing members, we have been able to generate hype around the event. In 2012 and 2013 &amp;amp; 2016 KFM covered the event, and in the past we’ve had Hectic99 presenters covering it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kfm.co.za/Articles/2016/04/21/montana-vikings-are-ready-for-24-hours-of-b-ball&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        Check out the insert from KFM
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2016/04/21/24hour/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2016/04/21/24hour/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MVBC Camp 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Junior MVBC Camp 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/camp15-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;camp pic&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year&#39;s camp will take on a different spin - as being in December, it will have a bit of a Christmas theme. Also, we are being adventurous, and taking on a 4 - 5hr trip to get there!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Koekenaap Cultural Centre&lt;/b&gt; is situated on the northern banks of the fertile Olifants River Valley between Vredendal and Lutzville. It was established in 1966 and is housed in a disused old farm school and is surrounded by vineyards close to the scenic environment of the flowers of Namakwaland. This facility is fully accessible for physically challenged people and caters mostly for the rural communities on the West Coast Region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, we rely a great deal on donations sourced from our club community and their networks to help maintain the success of this all important Annual Junior Camp and therefore appeal for your contributions towards our event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	You can contact us using the details at the bottom of the page.&lt;br /&gt;
	Many thanks,&lt;br /&gt;
	MVBC Exec.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/event/2015/12/04/camp-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/event/2015/12/04/camp-2015/</guid>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MVBC 24 Hour Basketball Marathon 2015!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;24 Hour Basketball Marathon 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our annual basketball marathon will be held on the 10th and 11th April 2015, starting at 16h00 on the friday evening (10th)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we plan to make it especially memorable, as it is the club&#39;s 20th anniversary!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check back here for regular updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/event/2015/04/10/24hour-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/event/2015/04/10/24hour-2015/</guid>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MVBC doing it for SA</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;MVBC doing it for SA&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/sa-team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SA Team&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to the guys selected to represent South Africa at the resent Quadrangular held at Wembley Stadium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From left we have Sivuyile &quot;Maloti&quot; Qavane, Thabile &quot;Godfrey&quot; Koti, and Craig &quot;Coach&quot; Daniels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done on this great achievement, and hopefully you guys will have a long fruitful career at national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach Craig is the assistant coach to the national mens team, which participated in the recent zone 6 qualifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2015/03/23/mvbc-sa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2015/03/23/mvbc-sa/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WE HAVE SNAPSCAN!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/snaplogo.png&quot; alt=&quot;snapscan&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;MVBC now accepts snapscan payments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/snapcode.png&quot; alt=&quot;snapscan&quot; class=&quot;fluid-l&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that we now accept snapscan payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this great facility, you can now make any sort of payment to the club without the hassle of setting up beneficiaries and logging onto your internet banking from your desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply download the app to your phone, snap the above barcode, and make a payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy, secure and effortless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2015/03/13/we-have-snapscan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2015/03/13/we-have-snapscan/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MVBC Camp 2014!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Junior MVBC Camp 2014&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/camp1-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;camp pic&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Montana Vikings Basketball Club’s (MVBC) Junior Camp is an important opportunity for us to positively influence the daily decision-making and life-style choices of our juniors away from the basketball court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concept originated by trying to find solutions to some of the many socio-economic challenges we face as a club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Junior Camp encourages our members from different demographics, social and cultural backgrounds to be together for a weekend, sharing life experiences, and learning from and with each other. Our club members come from a wide range of socio-economic and cultural backgrounds. Areas include Montana, Valhalla Park, Gugulethu, Nyanga, Heideveld, Manenberg, Phillipi as well as Grassy Park, Goodwood, Salt River, Rondebosch, Blouberg and Brackenfell. One of the main reasons for our club’s success is that we are a family, and we provide the home away from home environment to our members. The integration allows the less fortunate members with particularly financial difficulties to identify opportunities and to rise above their challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rely a great deal on donations sourced from our club community and their networks to help maintain the success of this all important Annual Junior Camp and therefore appeal for your contributions towards our event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/files/2014CampSponsorship.pdf&quot;&gt;SPONSORSHIP LETTER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/files/2014CampDonationList.pdf&quot;&gt;DONATION LIST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	You can contact us using the details at the bottom of the page.&lt;br /&gt;
	Many thanks,&lt;br /&gt;
	MVBC Exec.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/event/2014/07/18/camp-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/event/2014/07/18/camp-2014/</guid>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BNL Rookies</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Some Vikings made their BNL debut against the Panthers this weekend ...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/BNL1-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BNL Pic 2&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Cleve Dombas and Sivuyile &quot;Bam&quot; Mdekazi for making their Western Cape Mountaineers debuts this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them did fantastically well, and have a bright future at the next level. Keep it up ballers!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/BNL1-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BNL Pic 1&quot; class=&quot;fluid-c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleve, Bam, Godfrey and Maloti chilling before the game&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2014/07/10/bnl-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2014/07/10/bnl-update/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MVBC win it all</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;MVBC take the 8 thousand rand and the title!!!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Montana Vikings Basketball Club surged to victory in the inaugural Cape Basketball Championship on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vikings, a juggernaut in Cape basketball, lost just one game throughout the tournament to claim the trophy and R8000 in cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/8G-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8Gs Pic 1&quot; class=&quot;fluid-l&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Championship started at the Cape Peninsula University of Technology (CPUT) Cape Town campus with pool matches on Saturday. Vikings were drawn in Pool B along with CPUT Cats and CPUT Alumni, while Pool A comprised Constantia-based Hurricanes Basketball Club, the University of Cape Town (UCT) and the University of the Western Cape (UWC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vikings got their title charge going with a narrow 67-63 win over Cats before losing 54-51 to Alumni to finish second in their group, while Cats placed first. In Group A Hurricanes beat UWC 64-60 and UCT 64-38 to finish on top, while UWC finished second after beating UCT 66-48 in their other game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the scores and results from the group stages proved a poor reflection of the teams involved, as both the group winners were eliminated in the semi-finals. Hurricanes lost 72-50 to Vikings, while Cats were beaten 84-66 by UWC. Cats went on to beat Hurricanes 77-70 in the third-place play-off to claim the bronze medal. And Vikings took all the spoils after beating UWC 80-75 in the final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final of the women&amp;rsquo;s tournament finished with the CPUT Cats first and second teams battling it out for superiority. Both teams went into the final undefeated, finishing at the summit of their respective groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cats second team topped Pool A after defeating UCT 54-30 and Lethal Ladies 57-37, while Lethal Ladies were second after beating UCT 60-22. The Cats first team beat UWC 62-49 and Vikings 43-38, and Vikings finished second in the group after beating UWC 65-41 in their other match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first team dominated their semi-final fixture against Lethal Ladies, winning 68-38, while the second side scraped to a 49-45 win over Vikings. The Vikings women&amp;rsquo;s team could not emulate their men&amp;rsquo;s team by taking home a medal and lost 64-42 to Lethal Ladies in the third-place play-off. In the end, the CPUT first team were too strong and beat the second team 62-44 to take home the R8000 in cash and the trophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annual tournament was hosted by Platinum Media Group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2014/06/22/sl-tournament/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2014/06/22/sl-tournament/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maloti - the REAL MVP!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Maloti wins the MVP of the tournament&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mvbc.co.za/assets/images/blog/pics/8G-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8Gs Pic 2&quot; class=&quot;fluid-l&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Sivuyile &quot;Maloti&quot; Qavane, for being awarded the tournament MVP. Proving a thorn in the sides of all the teams we came up against, Maloti really used this tournament as his coming out party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets hope this fine form can carry on into the CTBA league, as well as his further development at BNL level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2014/06/22/sl-tournament-mvp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mvbc.co.za/blog/2014/06/22/sl-tournament-mvp/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
